Guide to the National Guardian Photographs PHOTOS.213
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
National Guardian Photographs
1948-1992
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
National Guardian
Jocz, Gregory
PHOTOS.213
54.6 Linear Feet in 108 manuscript boxes and 2 oversize flat boxes
The National Guardian (later known as The Guardian) was a radical leftist weekly newspaper published in New York City between 1948 and 1992. The National Guardian reported on labor, activism, reform, and social movements without particular party affiliations, advocating for a unified leftist party in the United States. Known for its independent and investigative journalism, the paper produced significant pieces on civil rights and the Cold War, and was one of the few publications to print news sympathetic to Julius and Ethel Rosenberg during their trial and execution, with much of the paper's reporting coming from William A. Reuben. This collection is comprised of the photograph files of the National Guardian, consisting of approximately 44,465 8x10 black-and-white photographic prints, along with some original cartoons and other graphic materials. The materials reflect the subject matter of the newspaper itself, reporting labor, activism, reform, and social movements.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Gregory Jocz in 2005. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 2005.041 and NPA.2005.122.
The accession number NPA.2005.050 is also associated with this collection.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Scope and Content Note
This collection is comprised of the photograph files of the National Guardian, consisting of approximately 44,465 8x10 black-and-white photographic prints, along with some original cartoons and other graphic materials. The materials reflect the subject matter of the newspaper itself, reporting on labor and the left without particular party affiliations, advocating for a unified leftist party in the United States. Known for its independent and investigative journalism, the paper produced numerous significant articles concerning civil rights and the Cold War, including coverage of Julius and Ethel Rosenberg's trial and execution. The photographs document both domestic and international events, with an emphasis on activism, reform, and social movements.
Related Archival Materials
Cedric Belfrage Papers (TAM 143)
Sally Belfrage Papers (TAM 189)
Historical/Biographical Note
The National Guardian (later known as The Guardian) was a radical leftist weekly newspaper published in New York City between 1948 and 1992. The paper was founded by James Aronson, Cedric Belfrage, and John T. McManus with the purpose of providing an alternative perspective to the mainstream media during the Cold War. The paper's early years focused on and supported New Deal programs and the New York American Labor Party (ALP). The National Guardian reported on labor, activism, reform, and social movements without particular party affiliations, advocating for a unified leftist party in the United States. Known for its independent and investigative journalism, the paper produced significant pieces on civil rights and the Cold War, and was one of the few publications to print news sympathetic to Julius and Ethel Rosenberg during their trial and execution, with much of the paper's reporting coming from William A. Reuben.
During the 1960s, the paper shifted directions toward the New Left, with Aronson selling his shares and the publication changing its name to the Guardian. In the 1970s, the Guardian supported Marxism-Leninism, calling for a new Marxist-Leninist party in the United States. The paper established Guardian Clubs for readers in the 1980s, which gave rise to competitor publications Frontline and Line of March. After years of declining circulation and financial difficulties, the paper ceased publication in 1992.
Counterculture -- United States -- Newspapers.; Black-and-white photographs.; United States -- Politics and government -- Newspapers.; Social movements -- United States -- Newspapers.; New Left -- United States -- Newspapers.; Peace movements -- United States -- Newspapers.; Jocz, Gregory
- Mozambique, 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 1-10)
- Mozambique, 1984-1992 (Box 1, Folder 11-21)
- Mozambique – Aid, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Mozambique – Children, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Mozambique – Crime, 1991-1991 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Mozambique – Culture, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Mozambique – Demos, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Mozambique – Economy, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Mozambique – Education, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Mozambique – Environment, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Mozambique – Government, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Mozambique – Famine, 1989-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Mozambique – Farms, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Mozambique – FRELIMO, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Mozambique – Health, 1990-1990 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Mozambique – Housing, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Mozambique – Infrastructure, 1988-1991 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Mozambique – International Relations, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Mozambique – Labor, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Mozambique – Media, 1990-1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Mozambique – Military, 1983-1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Mozambique – Opposition, 1991-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Mozambique – Personalities, 1987-1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Mozambique – Refugees, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Mozambique – Religion, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Mozambique – RENAMO, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Mozambique – Sports, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Mozambique – Transportation, 1989-1989 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Mozambique – Tourism, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Mozambique – War, 1984-1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Mozambique – Women, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Nambia, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- NATO/Warsaw Military, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Nepal, 1990-1990 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Nicaragua, 1981-1991 (Box 2, Folder 30-33)
- Nicaragua, 1981-1991 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- N. Korea, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Pakistan, 1984-1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Panama, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Peru, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Philippines, 1984-1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Poland, 1990-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Romania, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- South Africa, 1985-1990 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- S. Korea, 1953-1991 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Spain, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Soviet Union, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- U.S./Iraq War, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Venezuela, 1990-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Vietnam, 1979-1990 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- West Bank/Gaza, 1984-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- Yugoslavia, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Zaire, 1985-1990 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Zimbabwe, 1990-1990 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- International Personalities, 1984-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
- Personalities, 1984-1992 (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
- M. Harold Washington, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Jesse Jackson, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Domestic Personalities – General, 1984-1991 (Box 5, Folder 1-6)
- John Birch Society, 1961-1967 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Minutemen, 1966-1975 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Right-wing groups, misc., 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Demo – Racism, 1975-1975 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Ku Klux Klan, 1960-1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Corporate Corruption – Crime, 1961-1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Graf, 1955-1964 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Rackets – Crime (Including Mafia, Cosa Nostra), 1963-1969 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Volunteer Law Enforcers, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Weatherman, 1969-1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Police and Equipment, 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Bombings – Sabotage, 1968-1975 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Kent State, etc. Student (College) Protests, 1964-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Peace Summit, 1960-1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Peace, 1960-1960 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Transcontinental Walk for Peace, 1961-1961 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Anti-War, 1965-1965 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Washington, D.C. Demonstration for Peace and Against Air Strikes at North Vietnam and Against the War in Vietnam, 1965-1965 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Peace, 1962-1962 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
- Peace Women Strike for Peace, 1962-1962 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Peace-Geneva Disarmament Conference, 1966-1966 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- January – Peace – April, 1966-1966 (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
- Anti-War NYC, 1966-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Peace, 1966-1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Hiroshima and Hiroshima Demonstrations Worldwide, 1955-1960 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
- Parliamentary Union – Interparliamentary Union Conference – Belgrade, Yugoslavia, 1963-1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Bombing, 1964-1974 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Anti-War Demonstrations and Protest, 1961-1961 (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Anti-war Demonstrations, 1965-1972 (Box 7, Folder 8-10)
- Peace, 1961-1961 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Peace, 1966-1966 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
- War Crimes, 1967-1967 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Stock Market, 1929-1966 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Peace, 1967-1967 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Demo – War, 1971-1975 (Box 8, Folder 6-8)
- Peace, 1965-1965 (Box 8, Folder 9-10)
- Peace, 1961-1961 (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Peace, 1963-1963 (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Peace, Easter, 1961-1961 (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Moratorium, 1969-1969 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Peace–International War Crimes Tribunal Stockholm, Sweden, 1967-1967 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Counter-inauguration, 1969-1969 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Anti-War, 1967-1967 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Peace, 1967-1967 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Peace – Foreign Countries, 1967-1967 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Pentagon– demonstrations and protests, 1967-1967 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Afghanistan, 1960-1989 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Albania, 1981-1981 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Algeria, 1982-1988 (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Argentina, 1957-1988 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
- Australia, 1952-1988 (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Asia and Australia miscellaneous, 1984-1984 (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Austria, 1980-1985 (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Bahamas Barbados, 1980-1982 (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Bangladesh, 1974-1985 (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Bangladesh Population Control, 1972-1972 (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Belau, 1986-1986 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Belgium, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Belize, 1975-1994 (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Bermuda, 1981-1981 (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Bolivia, 1955-1989 (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Brazil, miscellaneous, 1955-1985 (Box 9, Folder 24-25)
- Brazil – Personalities, 1982-1989 (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Brazil, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Britain – Peace, 1982-1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Britain: Blacks, Poor, 1981-1988 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Britain – miscellaneous, 1982-1989 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
- Britain – Personalities, 1985-1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- U.K. Miners Britain, 1984-1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Bulgaria, 1980-1989 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- Burma, 1984-1988 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Caribbean, 1982-1985 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Recent China, 1989-1989 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- China – Personalities, 1975-1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- China – miscellaneous, 1959-1987 (Box 10, Folder 12-14)
- China – Tibet, 1989-1989 (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Columbia, 1974-1988 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- Costa Rica, 1974-1986 (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Cuba, 1970-1987 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Articles, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- Dot Supplies, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- Cuba Demonstrations within and support, 1971-1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- Military, 1961-1985 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Housing, 1960-1981 (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Religion, 1973-1985 (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Health, 1983-1987 (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Cuba – Personalities, 1984-1986 (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Women in Cuba, 1961-1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Labor in Cuba (Workers...), 1966-1986 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Cuba (by Nancy), 1959-1986 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Cyprus, 1981-1985 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Czechoslovakia, 1982-1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Czechoslovakia [Oversize], 1963-1973 (Box 11, Folder 14)
- Denmark, 1982-1986 (Box 11, Folder 15)
- Disarmament Int., 1984-1985 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Dominican Republic, 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 17)
- Dominican Republic, 1978-1985 (Box 11, Folder 18)
- Dominican Republic, 1961-1980 (Box 11, Folder 19-20)
- Dominica, 1965-1985 (Box 11, Folder 21)
- E. Timor, 1975-1976 (Box 11, Folder 22)
- Ecuador, 1979-1985 (Box 11, Folder 23)
- Egypt photo, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 24)
- Egypt, 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Equat. Guinea, 1982-1985 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- El Salvador – miscellaneous, 1981-1989 (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
- El Salvador – guerilla, liberated zones and left in general, 1982-1986 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- El Salvador (Popular Movement), 1983-1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- El Salvador (Labour), 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 7)
- El Salvador by Kufeld, 1985-1986 (Box 12, Folder 8)
- El Salvador armed forces (militia, army, civil guard), 1966-1984 (Box 12, Folder 9)
- VVAW, 1969-1973 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Native American Culture, 1949-1969 (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Native American Personalities, 1974-1986 (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Indians Sit-in, 1970-1978 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- U.S. Imperialism Graphics, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Hippies, 1967-1969 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Hippies, 1967-1970 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- S.D.S., 1966-1969 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
- Arab-Israeli Relations, 1969-1969 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Anti-War D.C., 1969-1969 (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Anti-War, 1968-1968 (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Anti-War, 1969-1969 (Box 13, Folder 9)
- Democratic Convention, 1968-1968 (Box 13, Folder 10)
- Misc. Demonstrations U.S., 1969-1983 (Box 13, Folder 11)
- Young Lords, 1970-1970 (Box 13, Folder 12)
- Young Lords Party, 1965-1975 (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Anti-War/Disarmament, 1978-1978 (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Ban-the-Bomb, 1960-1962 (Box 13, Folder 15)
- International Industrialists Conference, 1966-1969 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Anti-Dow, 1969-1969 (Box 13, Folder 17)
- International Demons, 1979-1980 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- Anti-Nazi, 1960-1966 (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Prepositions 13, 1978-1978 (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Disabled, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Miscellaneous U.S. Graphics, 1976-1979 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
- Foreign Policy, 1969-1975 (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Health Care, 1966-1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Stop the Draft Week, 1968-1968 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Newark, NJ – Ghetto Rebellions, 1967-1967 (Box 14, Folder 6)
- Wallace – For and Against, 1968-1968 (Box 14, Folder 7)
- Anti-War, 1966-1966 (Box 14, Folder 8)
- Peace – Anti-War Demonstrations, 1967-1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Hard Times Conference –Chicago, 1975-1975 (Box 14, Folder 10)
- Kent State, 1970-1980 (Box 14, Folder 11-12)
- Student Demonstrations and Anti-War, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 13)
- Student Demonstrations, 1970-1979 (Box 14, Folder 14-15)
- Student (College) Protests, 1960-1969 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Student (College) Protests, 1960-1969 (Box 15, Folder 1-4)
- May Day Actions, 1973-1973 (Box 15, Folder 5)
- May Day International (Industry and Labor), 1923-1960 (Box 15, Folder 6)
- School Budget Cutbacks, 1976-1976 (Box 15, Folder 7)
- Elijah Muhammad Leader of the Black Muslims, 1964-1964 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Nov. 4 Coalition, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 9)
- Left-Wing Religious, 1956-1972 (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous Groups, 1967-1975 (Box 15, Folder 11)
- VIPs – U.S., 1972-1978 (Box 15, Folder 12)
- Nukes, 1979-1979 (Box 15, Folder 13)
- America First, 1941-1941 (Box 15, Folder 14)
- American National Party-Organizations and Groups, 1961-1962 (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Asian-Americans, 1969-1969 (Box 15, Folder 16)
- Alianza Federal de Pueblos Libres, 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 17)
- DuBois Club, 1966-1966 (Box 15, Folder 18)
- Left-Wing Groups Miscellaneous, 1959-1965 (Box 15, Folder 19)
- Moral Re-Armament Assembly, 1957-1961 (Box 15, Folder 20)
- National Conference on New Politics, 1967-1967 (Box 15, Folder 21)
- National Student Association, 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Peace and Freedom Party [Empty?], undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
- Student National Coordinating Committee Formerly Student National Coordinating Committee, 1966-1966 (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Vietnam Day Committee, 1966-1966 (Box 15, Folder 25)
- CP, 1920-1966 (Box 15, Folder 26)
- Communist Part, 1941-1966 (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Viet Vets (for Peace), 1967-1967 (Box 15, Folder 28)
- Young Americans for Freedom, 1962-1966 (Box 15, Folder 29)
- Job Discrimination, 1960-1960 (Box 16, Folder 1)
- American Nazi Party, 1961-1967 (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
- Yippies and Crazies Youth International Party, 1968-1969 (Box 16, Folder 4)
- Evictions and Squatters, 1954-1957 (Box 16, Folder 5)
- Interracial Marriage, 1967-1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Peace – Fort Hood GIs, 1966-1966 (Box 16, Folder 7)
- Demo before 70 War, 1967-1975 (Box 16, Folder 8)
- [Oversized] Mine Workers, 1973-1973 (Box 50, Folder 1)
- Watts Riot, LA –Civil Rights, 1965-1965 (Box 16, Folder 9)
- Ohio, 1965-1966 (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
- Riots, 1965-1982 (Box 16, Folder 12-13)
- Black Struggle, 1970-1970 (Box 16, Folder 14)
- BAKKE Black Struggle, 1978-1978 (Box 16, Folder 15)
- Atlanta Murderers – Williams, 1981-1981 (Box 16, Folder 16)
- Black Struggle, 1971-1974 (Box 16, Folder 17)
- Black Struggle, 1975-1975 (Box 16, Folder 18)
- Black Struggle, 1976-1976 (Box 16, Folder 19)
- Black Struggle, 1977-1977 (Box 16, Folder 20)
- Wilmington V Ben Chavis Ten, 1977-1978 (Box 16, Folder 21)
- Blacks and Other Minorities, 1964-1980 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Racism, 1976-1978 (Box 16, Folder 23)
- Black Struggle, 1979-1986 (Box 16, Folder 24)
- Wiley, 1970-1980 (Box 16, Folder 25)
- Civil Liberties – Rights Mack Charies Parker – Lynching, 1959-1959 (Box 17, Folder 1)
- Georgia – Ghetto Rebellions, 1967-1974 (Box 17, Folder 2)
- Blacks in Sports, 1949-1961 (Box 17, Folder 3-4)
- Angela Davis – Ruchell Magee Trial, Soledad Brothers, 1970-1972 (Box 17, Folder 5)
- Women's Issues, 1978-1979 (Box 17, Folder 6)
- Ku Klux Klan and other Racist Groups, 1960-1980 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Women's Jobs and Personalities, 1956-1984 (Box 17, Folder 8-10)
- Women, 1977-1984 (Box 17, Folder 11)
- Abortion, 1977-1989 (Box 18, Folder 1-3)
- Women Demonstrations, 1989-1989 (Box 18, Folder 4)
- Women, 1984-1989 (Box 18, Folder 5-6)
- Roe V. Wade Demo-Union Square, 1988-1988 (Box 18, Folder 7)
- Anti-Poverty Programs, 1960-1969 (Box 18, Folder 8)
- Demonstrations Women, 1986-1986 (Box 18, Folder 9)
- Civil Rights Demonstrations, 1962-1969 (Box 18, Folder 10)
- Black Struggle, 1968-1968 (Box 18, Folder 11)
- Poor Peoples March– Civil Rights, 1968-1968 (Box 19, Folder 1-2)
- Black Struggle, 1967-1967 (Box 19, Folder 3)
- Black Struggle, 1969-1969 (Box 19, Folder 4)
- Black Struggle, 1954-1956 (Box 19, Folder 5)
- Black Struggle, 1964-1964 (Box 19, Folder 6-7)
- James Meredith, Black Struggle, 1962-1963 (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Freedom Democratic Party Mississippi, 1965-1965 (Box 19, Folder 9)
- Alabama– Civil Rights, 1965-1965 (Box 19, Folder 10)
- Women Demonstrations 1988, 1988-1988 (Box 19, Folder 11)
- The U.S. Weapons in South Vietnam, 1966-1975 (Box 20, Folder 1-3)
- The U.S. Air Bases in South Vietnam, 1966-1975 (Box 20, Folder 4-5)
- During the Liberation of South Vietnam, 1966-1985 (Box 20, Folder 6)
- The Celebration of Armed Forces After the Liberation of South Vietnam, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 7)
- The G.I. in Action Before the Vietnamese Liberation, 1966-1972 (Box 20, Folder 8-10)
- The G.I. in Action Before the Vietnamese Liberation, 1966-1972 (Box 21, Folder 1)
- The U.S. Marine Bases, 1965-1985 (Box 21, Folder 2)
- South Vietnam People and Student Demonstrations, 1963-1976 (Box 21, Folder 3-5)
- Foreign Demonstrations Against Vietnam War, 1966-1972 (Box 21, Folder 6)
- South Vietnamese Monks, Demonstration, 1966-1985 (Box 21, Folder 7)
- Politics of South Vietnam During U.S. War, 1965-1974 (Box 21, Folder 8)
- The U.S. War of Destruction and Defoliation in South Vietnam Area, 1965-1974 (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
- The U.S. War of Destruction and Defoliation in South Vietnam Area, 1965-1974 (Box 22, Folder 1)
- Vietnamese Prisoner in South Vietnam During the U.S. War, 1967-1973 (Box 22, Folder 2)
- The Victims of U.S. Crimes in South Vietnam, 1966-1969 (Box 22, Folder 3)
- Daily Ways of Life of the People in South Vietnam Before the Liberation, 1966-1975 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
- Daily Ways of Life of the People in South Vietnam Before the Liberation, 1964-1978 (Box 22, Folder 6-7)
- The Soldier's Way of Life After Fighting in South Vietnam, 1953-1975 (Box 22, Folder 8)
- The Soldier's Way of Life After Fighting in South Vietnam, 1953-1975 (Box 23, Folder 1)
- Children in South Vietnam During U.S. War, 1966-1985 (Box 23, Folder 2-3)
- Daily Ways of Life of the People in South Vietnam Before the Liberation, 1966-1985 (Box 23, Folder 4-5)
- Vietnam/Cambodia/Laos, 1965-1976 (Box 23, Folder 6)
- The G.I. in Action Before the Vietnamese Liberation, 1963-1972 (Box 23, Folder 7-8)
- Vietnamese Refugees During U.S. War, 1967-1978 (Box 23, Folder 9)
- The G.I. in Action Before the Vietnamese Liberation, 1966-1984 (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
- Anti-Apartheid, 1984-1987 (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
- Anti-War, Black Panther, Protests, 1957-1971 (Box 24, Folder 5)
- Disarmament Actions, 1983-1983 (Box 24, Folder 6)
- Demonstrations – Anti-Draft, 1979-1984 (Box 24, Folder 7)
- Demo – Bork, 1987-1987 (Box 24, Folder 8)
- El Salvador Economy, 1984-1989 (Box 24, Folder 9)
- Anti-Apartheid, 1985-1985 (Box 24, Folder 10)
- Anti-Apartheid Demonstrations, 1988-1988 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Anti-Apartheid, 1985-1985 (Box 24, Folder 12)
- Anti-Apartheid, 1985-1985 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- Anti-Apartheid, 1986-1986 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- Anti-Apartheid, 1987-1987 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Demonstrations Anti-Nuke, 1988-1988 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- AIDS Demonstrations, 1989-1989 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- ABC Strike California, 1988-1988 (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Demonstrations, 1985-1985 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Demonstrations – AIDS, 1987-1988 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Demonstrations – Animal Rights, 1989-1989 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Disarmament Demonstrations, 1982-1985 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Disarmament/Hiro-Nagasaki Day Protests, 1985-1985 (Box 25, Folder 11)
- AIDS Testing, 1987-1987 (Box 25, Folder 12)
- AIDS Demonstrations, 1988-1988 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Demonstrations – miscellaneous, International, 1980-1987 (Box 25, Folder 14-15)
- Demonstrations – miscellaneous, International, 1980-1987 (Box 26, Folder 1)
- Anti-Contra Aid, 1985-1985 (Box 26, Folder 2)
- Demonstrations/Central America, 1985-1987 (Box 26, Folder 3-7)
- Anti-Contra Aid Demonstrations, 1987-1987 (Box 26, Folder 8)
- Contra Aid Protests, 1988-1988 (Box 26, Folder 9)
- Nica Contra Aid, 1984-1986 (Box 26, Folder 10-12)
- Students, 1989-1989 (Box 26, Folder 13)
- Demonstrations VS Bush, 1989-1989 (Box 26, Folder 14)
- Demonstrations Black, 1965-1983 (Box 27, Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, 1981-1986 (Box 27, Folder 2)
- Demonstrations African Support, 1980-1986 (Box 27, Folder 3)
- Miscellaneous Demonstrations and Protests, 1949-1989 (Box 27, Folder 4-11)
- Miscellaneous Demonstrations and Protests, 1949-1989 (Box 28, Folder 1-9)
- Miscellaneous Demonstrations and Protests, 1949-1989 (Box 29, Folder 1-9)
- Free Press/Censorship, 1989-1989 (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Demonstrations – Anti-CIA, 1985-1987 (Box 30, Folder 2)
- CIA Demonstrations, 1987-1987 (Box 30, Folder 3)
- Demonstrations – Anti-Contra Aid, 1986-1986 (Box 30, Folder 42830)
- Democratic Presidential Candidates 1984, 1982-1984 (Box 30, Folder 6)
- Central America/ Contra Aid, 1988-1988 (Box 30, Folder 42925)
- Farmers Strikes, 1977-1977 (Box 30, Folder 10)
- Livestock, 1968-1974 (Box 30, Folder 11)
- Agriculture Equipment (Industry and Labor), 1965-1965 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Farms Old and New, 1947-1974 (Box 30, Folder 13)
- Native Americans, 1980-1981 (Box 30, Folder 14)
- Puerto Ricans in New York City, 1959-1978 (Box 30, Folder 15)
- Women's Struggle, 1975-1980 (Box 30, Folder 16-17)
- Economy and Poverty, 1967-1978 (Box 30, Folder 18)
- Working Women, 1979-1979 (Box 30, Folder 19)